♪ Pink hands so fine ♪
♪ Gold-branded wine ♪
♪ Spring paints willows green;
palace walls can't confine ♪
♪ East wind unfair ♪
♪ Happy times rare ♪
♪ In my heart, sad thoughts throng ♪
♪ We've severed for years long ♪
♪ Wrong, wrong, wrong ♪
Si Jin
Episode 40
I'm no groveling
supplicant,
yet no one
in this world has ever
understood me
or loved me.
Still, I cannot be called defeated.
From this day forward,
you will never forget Rongyang.
Father!
♪ Life is like flowers,
blooming and fading with the seasons ♪
♪ Wind leaves marks,
swaying in the breeze ♪
♪ I don't wish for favors from the heavens ♪
♪ To enjoy a blessed life ♪
♪ I only wish to be unburdened ♪
♪ Fate's been written; we're its slaves ♪
♪ I dare not look back
at the road I came from ♪
♪ As the sun sets, the wise seek redemption ♪
♪ I only wish to wake up one day ♪
♪ I won't lose with myself in the game ♪
♪ Alas, is it too late
to stop indulging myself ♪
♪ Is it too difficult to be free from sorrow ♪
♪ How many regrets are left ♪
♪ To be remedied ♪
♪ A small greed forms an unbreakable tie ♪
♪ Is the resting shore too shallow ♪
♪ Is the yearning in my heart too distant ♪
♪ The wildflowers bloom across the mountains ♪
♪ Yet I remain trapped ♪
♪ A shared bond, a tragic ending ♪
♪ Is the resting shore too shallow ♪
♪ Is the yearning in my heart too distant ♪
♪ The wildflowers bloom across the mountains ♪
♪ Yet I remain trapped ♪
♪ A shared bond, a tragic ending ♪
♪ A shared bond ♪
♪ A tragic ending ♪
(Tiande Hall)
(The rebel, Marquis Changxing, )
(is sentenced to death by a thousand cuts.)
(Grand Princess Rongyang sacrificed herself)
(to protect the Emperor.)
(She's honored as Grand Princess Xianjing)
(in the Imperial Mausoleum.)
(Cui Xu's appointed Duke of the State.)
(Jiang Zhan, General of Defense.)
(Long Dan, Chief Imperial Insignia Guard.)
(Xie Yinlou, Commandant of Capital Security.)
(Zhen Heng, Vice Prime Minister.)
I meant to fly the kite
to send you a message,
but...
I know.
I know it all.
Still,
I need to see for myself you're fine.
I thought I'd never see you again.
Fuqing,
I want to marry you
and grow old with you.
Will you marry me?
You once asked me
why I refused the betrothal
by His Majesty.
Why did you
refuse to marry me that day?
Back then,
I only saw you as a student.
I wouldn't dare hope for more.
But after this near-death experience,
I realize
you're always in my heart.
It beats for you.
Others might've only seen
that you're soft and delicate
while in my eyes,
you're brave
and tough.
I'm conquered by you.
Although you were in the dark,
you tried to light up others.
You'd protect them
in your own way
despite the fact
that you were suffering in silence.
I accept you for who you are.
I just want you
to be happy,
free,
and healthy.
Our feelings are mutual.
So will you marry me?
Yes, I'll marry you!
Thank you for everything, Jin.
It's all thanks to General Cui.
You little cheat!
Don't play games with me.
Cui Xu came
because of Jiang Si, right?
She's a wonderful girl.
You have good taste.
I appreciate your compliment.
By the way, Father,
I've returned
the Jade Seal
you entrusted me with in perilous time.
You've grown up.
What plans do you have?
Tell me about them.
I want to go to Nanwu
to see Jiang Si.
Go to Nanwu?
Yes.
I'll agree to anything
but not that.
This isn't the best time to go there.
When... when is the best time?
(Tiande Hall)
I'll never set foot
in Tiande Hall again.
As for the timing,
that'll be
your decision to make.
Over the years,
because of Rongyang,
your mother has fought with me a lot.
After this latest scare,
I want to spend some time with her
and take her away to relax.
(Tiande Hall)
(Nanwu)
Grand Elder,
these are the finest spices.
They're rarely seen in Dazhou.
Nanwu
abounds with such spices.
Look. Incense is made in every household.
Grand Elder,
have you considered
encouraging the locals to do business?
Do business?
Nanwu has
never had any merchants,
only farmers and soldiers.
Military expenses
can be a heavy burden.
If there's no war,
the soldiers can
return home
to make a living.
As for farmers,
your topography
isn't suitable for farming.
What would we eat without it?
Farming is for self-sufficiency.
If you couldn't even support yourselves,
you had to join the army and fight
with your lives for more resources.
Actually,
there's a better option
for you.
Nanwu is rich in spices,
which are in high demand in Dazhou
despite their high prices.
If the people here
start doing business
by bringing those rare spices
to Dazhou
in exchange for what they need,
that way, even without farming,
they will
lead a better life.
Who'd
risk their lives in battle instead?
Do you mean
to sell these spices
to Dazhou
for food, ironware,
and other necessities?
Everyone will get what they need.
Our people's lives
will be greatly improved.
In that case,
the 100-year-long clash
will finally end.
Perhaps it is a better option.
Alright. We'll do it your way.
Let's carry it out
as the Saintess said.
So heavy!
- Don't drop it.
- Yes.
♪ It's a long story;
we'll take different paths in this life ♪
♪ The world is changing;
may we find where we belong ♪
♪ I want nothing else; I'll stop for you ♪
Chief, it's...
Your Majesty,
it's too heavy.
Wear it for a day
and it might bend your neck.
♪ Mottled fate reaches the end ♪
♪ Hope to embrace eternity with you ♪
May you be blessed
with many children
to continue the family line
and make your clan thrive.
Complete!
♪ Forgetting the past, how many can make it ♪
Put them away.
Are you sure?
♪ Looking at the past ♪
Wait until she comes back to try them on.
Yes.
Jiang Si.
Chuchu, sit with me.
My dear Saintess,
you've worked nonstop
for Nanwu.
It's time to take a break.
Chuchu,
I invited you over
to tell you something.
Could I trouble you to return to Dazhou?
I can go back to Ling'an?
What about you?
Won't you come along?
I can't return yet.
When you get back,
tell my sister and others
about the situation here.
I need their help.
Then find out what spices
the rich and powerful in Ling'an prefer.
Please make a list of them
and send it to me.
Sure.
Once Dazhou
and Nanwu can trade with each other,
don't forget my help.
I won't!
Take a look.
These are the rare spices in Nanwu
I've collected lately.
To Yu Jin.
I've made a pact
with Nanwu for a year.
During this period,
I'll stay there
and make Nanwu prosper
as never before
without going to war.
I'm confident of it.
She didn't mention me at all.
Your Majesty,
Minister Zhen came to see you.
Send him in.
Grand Princess Fuqing also came.
- Zhen Heng
- Fuqing
- greets you, Your Majesty.
You came together, huh?
What's up?
I, Zhen Heng,
sincerely hope to marry
Grand Princess Fuqing
to forever tie the knot.
People call me rigid, dull,
and stubborn as a mule.
They aren't wrong.
But only Fuqing
accepts all my shortcomings
and truly admires me.
Your Majesty,
after Marquis Changxing's rebel earlier,
it became clearer to me
that I should cherish the most
the one by my side.
I promise to devote my life
to Grand Princess Fuqing.
I'll respect her and love her.
Please grant our marriage, Your Majesty.
Do you, who are by his side,
think the same?
His wish is my wish.
Minister Zhen,
I've never seen you like this before.
Please stop making fun of me.
Get up already.
Thanks, Your Majesty.
Don't act like Romeo and Juliet.
If it got out,
others would call me inhuman.
Minister Zhen,
Fuqing,
I'll attend
your wedding in person
and give you
this, this, and this.
It's as fine as emerald and jade,
the best of the best.
I handpicked it
for you in particular.
Oh,
and this too.
A gold-clad turtle with jade shards.
Those gifts you said
seem quite familiar.
But I think
nothing can be better
than your approval.
Granted.
You have my approval!
Thanks, Your Majesty.
Look, Grand Elder.
These goods
will be sent to Dazhou
as well as those spices.
Your Majesty,
a letter for you.
Please find the attached book
of Nanwu's herbs.
It includes various prescriptions
for unusual diseases, too.
They can help our people.
(To Yu Jin)
Although reform is never easy,
it's started making Nanwu better.
I need hydraulicians from Dazhou
to help Nanwu build dikes and dams
to protect their farmland.
Also... I miss you
and Er'niu.
Did she write to me
only to help Nanwu
build dikes and dams?
If one day,
I leave Ling'an,
I'll go to a beautiful place
and
buy a small farm and a cottage
to settle down
and lead a simple yet free life.
I'll
bring with me my father,
my siblings,
Chuchu, Aman,
Long Dan,
and...
and Er'niu!
Good. Very well.
And you too.
Will you go with me?
Have someone send Er'niu to her.
She misses him.
Yes.
(Report)
(Fragrant and Sparse)
Poor pigeon.
It has to fly so far only to send two words.
Miss you.
You're the Emperor.
Couldn't you bring more attendants?
These books aren't enough, are they?
Still not enough?
Even if Si read all day,
it'd take her years to finish them all.
I bought all the books
I could find over there.
What do you think? Are they enough?
They seem ample altogether.
Right?
Let's check other places.
Other places?
(The Commentary of Zuo
on the Spring and Autumn Annals)
Pack them all and send them to her.
Yes.
(To Jiang Si)
Are you going to leave tomorrow morning?
I've packed everything.
I came to
say goodbye to you, Mother.
Everything in the North is different
from that of Ling'an.
Although it's your ancestral home,
you've never been there before.
You've suddenly been appointed there
as the Protectorate General.
I wonder if you
can adapt to that place.
Don't worry, Mother.
The North is vast
but underdeveloped.
Jin entrusted it to me
and said I shall do what I see fit
to improve it.
That's all I need to hear.
In the past, with the Crown Prince above you,
you were unappreciated.
Now, you have a chance
to realize your ambition.
However, I'm not sure
when I'll come back.
I can no longer keep you company
as before.
Jin might still hold a grudge against you.
That concerns me the most.
Him?
He's been visiting me regularly.
Really?
He doesn't say much
and leaves after paying his respects,
but
he comes regardless.
Very well.
That's at least a good start.
I think so, too.
Zhang,
keep walking with me
when you still can.
Yes, Your Highness.
Your father
and I will also leave soon to travel.
(Earl Dongping's Mansion)
Zhan,
do you need to bring
a few maids with you
to take care of
your daily life?
Father,
I'm going to Yangui
as the Envoy to the Southwest
to make sure both sides
trade safely.
I'm not going on a trip.
Besides,
I have arms and legs.
I can look after myself.
I'm more worried about you.
When Si and I are away,
take good care of yourself.
Act your age,
alright?
You'll be going there
all alone.
I can't stop
worrying about you.
Who told you I'd go alone?
Who's going with you?
Who else?
Is Chuchu going to join you?
I guess.
Good for you.
Look at her
willing to
go so far with you.
You should marry her
as soon as possible!
Be committed.
You should learn
from me.
Stop nagging.
We have our own plan.
What plan?
You don't need a plan for such things.
You'll leave soon.
Congratulations
on being the Envoy.
We can hardly
see each other again, right?
I guess.
Is there anything you want to
say to me?
Chuchu,
I've been wanting to tell you...
I...
No.
What are you going to do next?
Me?
The same as before.
It's a big world.
I'll enjoy it as much as possible
and explore it.
I can't be
confined to one place.
It makes sense.
You're a heroine after all.
May you
live your best life
every day.
Well,
Jiang Zhan,
after everything
we went through together,
I realize although I want to
be a heroine
and see the world,
I enjoy the most
the life as it is
to be with my love
and do what I love.
Be with your love
and do...
No one else is here!
You love me?
I love you!
What?
I didn't get that.
I love you!
I love you! I love you!
It's a horse!
(One Year Later)
(Earl Dongping's Mansion)
All the ingredients are ready.
I see flowers!
Si loves flower cakes the most.
Add more honey.
Yes, Grandmother.
- We've got everything.
- Good.
I wonder
if she's gained or lost weight.
I miss her dearly.
Will she come back
and leave again?
- Grandmother.
Welcome back, girls!
I miss all of you!
We miss you, too.
Have a seat.
Sure.
Over the past year,
I've read a lot of books.
In Yang's Family Prescriptions,
I found one for leg problems.
I want to try it to treat your legs.
How sweet.
You care so much about me.
You've changed so much
since we met last time.
You look more like
a refined scholar
than an ordinary girl.
I'm flattered.
It's all thanks to Si.
Without her,
I wouldn't have taken the first step.
Let bygones be bygones.
From now on,
you'll lead a wonderful life.
Yinlou greets you, Lady Jiang.
Commandant Xie.
Welcome, Commandant Xie.
Yi needs to pound
more flowers to make flower cakes.
Go and help her.
What are you waiting for?
Give me a hand.
Sure.
Anmou,
you're terrible
at making dough.
Look how watery it is.
We're making flower cakes,
not flower paste.
You only talk the talk.
Do it yourself.
No problem. I'll make it.
It's so thin.
Add some flour.
Stop, stop, stop!
How much are you going to pour?
How much do you need?
I said add some flour.
A tad would be enough.
- I did.
- You poured a whole bag!
I added water, too...
Enough, you two.
Look what you two have done.
The dough is
getting bigger and bigger.
I know, right?
We can make
enough flower cakes
for everyone in town.
Use more strength.
See? Mother is doing much better.
(Taiji Hall, Tiande Hall)
There's something
I've kept from you.
We checked it out.
Your mother, Su Ke, was born in Nanwu
before Mr. Su adopted her at the border.
Since then,
you've been bonded with Nanwu.
The Saintess has to
go through life and death.
You must've seen
the past before becoming it.
You're right.
I rose from death
before having that totem.
This classified scroll
records the secrets
of the Saintess.
(Yu)
It's Nanwu's ancient spell.
If yearnings overlap,
one may trade one's life
for a one-in-a-million chance
to revive one's love.
It was Yu Jin.
He bet his life
on the slim chance of changing my fate.
Yes.
He lost not only his life
but also all his memories of you.
♪ Shattering the dreams ♪
♪ How many petals fell, I count ♪
♪ It equals the times I think about you ♪
Darling,
I miss you so much.
I miss you a lot, too.
♪ I can't forget about you ♪
(Yu Jin has been)
(my one and only love.)
♪ During my lifetime ♪
♪ Can I still make it through the long night ♪
♪ I fear that we'll part again ♪
I dreamed of holding you like this
a million times,
but every time I woke up,
I was here all alone.
Come to think of it,
during all those years
when I guarded the border,
I was alone, too,
but I never felt lonely.
Relax.
You won't feel lonely anymore.
I'm back.
That depends on if you'll leave again.
♪ The past fades as old dreams return ♪
I won't.
♪ I can't forget about you ♪
♪ However long the road is ♪
♪ No matter the cost,
I'll try to restore ♪
♪ The sealed memories ♪
I had a dream last night.
I saw
we built a home in Ling'an.
Were you homesick again?
What was our home like there?
There was you, of course,
and all our family.
Everyone was there.
Did I have to go on
guarding the border?
In that dream,
Dazhou and Nanwu made peace.
No more war.
People on both sides
led a happy and peaceful life.
I can't wait
for that day to come.
How I wish
we had made peace
decades ago.
That way,
your exile to the border
as a baby,
your cruel experience
on the battlefield as a teenager,
and all your suffering
would've been avoided.
Actually,
it was exactly such suffering
that led me to you bit by bit.
I was born into this world
to find you and bond with you.
(Taiji Hall)
(Tiande Hall)
The Empress has arrived!
I, Jiang Si,
humbly accept His Majesty's grace
to be crowned Empress.
I'll devoutly manage the harem
and set an example for the realm.
My gratitude for His Majesty's grace.
♪ From place to place ♪
♪ I drift in the world alone ♪
♪ The cool breeze comes and goes ♪
♪ I dare to love and hate ♪
Kneel!
♪ Ask the day and the night ♪
Long live, Your Majesty!
Long live,
Your Highness!
Bow!
Bow again!
♪ In the end, we're still together ♪
♪ Like shadows ♪
♪ We're brave enough to advance together ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ And stars ♪
(The End)
♪ From place to place ♪
♪ I drift in the world alone ♪
♪ The cool breeze comes and goes ♪
♪ I dare to love and hate ♪
♪ Ask the day and the night ♪
♪ If they saw a glimmer fall and take root ♪
♪ Growing between us ♪
♪ And breeding love ♪
♪ Smile at each other for the future ♪
♪ In the end, we're still together ♪
♪ Like shadows ♪
♪ We're brave enough to advance together ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ And stars ♪
♪ Don't ask what our fate is ♪
♪ Let life carve the growth rings ♪
♪ We'll reach the end eventually ♪
♪ All will bloom in spring ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ Smile at each other for the future ♪
♪ We travel at night in the cold ♪
♪ The moonlight shines like water ♪
♪ Those in love will have sweet dreams ♪
♪ Cherish each other in the future ♪
♪ Time goes by, but memories remain ♪
♪ Take a look to remember everything ♪
♪ We will see flowers fill the city again ♪